- Where is he? - Hey, Ho-jin.
- 그 사람은 어디 있지? - 안녕하세요, 호진님.
He's been crying for an hour.
그는 한 시간 동안 울고 있었습니다.
Jin-suk.
진숙.
Get up, will you?
일어나요, 그렇죠?
Hey, Ho-jin.
안녕하세요, 호진님.
Why are you crying in public? You're embarrassing yourself. Let's go.
왜 공개적으로 울고 있습니까? 당신은 당황스럽습니다. 갑시다.
Guess what? Shin Ji-sun said I broke up with her first.
추측해 보세요. 신지선이 말했다. 나는 그녀와 먼저 헤어졌다.
But I never did.
그러나 나는 결코 그렇게 하지 않았습니다.
She told me to think carefully, but I swear I never did.
잘 생각해보라고 하더군요, 하지만 난 한 번도 그런 적이 없다고 맹세해요.
Sure. Let's think about it at home.
확신하는. 집에서 생각해 봅시다.
Come on. Up you go.
어서 해봐요. 올라가세요.
I'm so angry and frustrated.
너무 화가 나고 답답해요.
When did I ever say that?
내가 언제 그런 말을 했나요?
I get it. Just walk straight.
알겠습니다. 그냥 똑바로 걸어가세요.
Okay.
좋아요.
Walk straight.
똑바로 걸어가세요.
Jin-suk.
진숙.
Have you sobered up a bit? Shall I drive you home?
좀 정신 차렸나요? 집까지 데려다 드릴까요?
Here.
여기.
I don't want it.
나는 그것을 원하지 않습니다.
Whenever I'd get drunk, Ji-sun would come pick me up.
술에 취했을 때마다, 지선이가 데리러 올 거에요.
What was that?
그게 뭐였지?
I'm just so heartbroken
난 그냥 너무 가슴이 아팠어
that I'm sharing my sadness with the world.
내 슬픔을 공유하고 있다는 걸 세상과 함께.
Does that make you feel better?
그러면 기분이 좋아지나요?
Yes.
예.
Expressing my emotions outwardly makes me feel better.
내 감정을 겉으로 표현하는 것 기분이 좋아집니다.
I bet people like you,
당신 같은 사람들이 있을 거라고 장담해요.
who bottle up their feelings and deal with them alone,
자신의 감정을 억누르는 사람 혼자서 그들을 처리하고,
would never understand.
결코 이해하지 못할 것입니다.
You're right.
당신 말이 맞아요.
I don't understand it.
나는 그것을 이해하지 못한다.
Because I'd be burdening others with my emotions.
왜냐하면 내가 다른 사람에게 부담을 줄 것이기 때문이다. 내 감정으로.
I don't understand you either, you cold-blooded jerk.
나도 당신을 이해하지 못합니다. 이 냉혈한 놈아.
Not expressing my feelings doesn't mean they're not there.
내 감정을 표현하지 않는 것 그들이 거기에 없다는 뜻은 아닙니다.
Or that they're easy to get over.
아니면 극복하기 쉽다는 것입니다.
Are you posting a photo?
사진을 올리는 건가요?
If you are, make sure the brand-sponsored watch is in it.
그렇다면 꼭 확인해보세요 브랜드 후원 시계가 그 안에 있습니다.
By the way, Mu-hee, Nanami reached out to me.
그런데 무희 씨, 나나미가 나에게 손을 내밀었다.
She and Hiro arrived in Korea today.
그녀와 히로는 오늘 한국에 도착했습니다.
Did she?
그녀는 그랬나요?
I guess he has work in Korea.
아무래도 그 사람은 한국에 일이 있는 것 같아요.
She actually asked about your schedule.
그녀는 실제로 당신의 일정에 대해 물었습니다.
Maybe he's here to see you.
어쩌면 그 사람이 당신을 만나러 여기 온 것일 수도 있어요.
Me? Why?
나? 왜?
Didn't you say you met Hiro on the plane?
비행기에서 히로를 만났다고 하지 않았나요?
Are you sure nothing happened?
정말 아무 일도 일어나지 않았나요?
Right.
오른쪽.
I did see him...
나는 그를 봤어...
but I was so out of sorts then.
하지만 그때는 내가 너무 정신이 없었어요.
I crashed after a glass of wine.
나는 와인 한 잔을 마시고 추락했습니다.
Maybe you slipped up while you were drunk.
어쩌면 술에 취해 미끄러졌을 수도 있습니다.
You were chasing Ho-jin around like a madwoman
호진이를 쫓아다녔잖아 미친 여자처럼
until you totally lost it.
완전히 잃어버릴 때까지.
You're right.
당신 말이 맞아요.
I ran after him like a madwoman
나는 미친 여자처럼 그 사람을 쫓아갔어
and sealed the deal.
그리고 거래를 성사시켰습니다.
Well, if your fate is sealed,
뭐, 운명이 정해져 있다면,
can you stop posting cloudy skies and raindrops that look like tears?
흐린 하늘 좀 그만 올릴 수 있어? 그리고 눈물같은 빗방울?
It's obvious who you posted these for,
누구를 위해 이 글을 올렸는지는 분명합니다.
but he's not the type to look at that stuff.
하지만 그 사람은 그런 사람이 아니야 그 물건을 보려고.
Have you
당신은
met Mr. Joo Ho-jin since then?
그 이후로 주호진씨를 만났나요?
I haven't seen him, but we've talked.
나는 그를 본 적이 없지만 우리는 이야기를 나눴습니다.
On the phone and by text.
전화와 문자로.
About what?
무엇에 대해서?
Well, you know...
글쎄요...
Hey, wait. You can't just check my phone.
잠깐만요. 내 전화만 확인하면 안 돼요.
You even memorized my lock pattern?
내 자물쇠 패턴도 외웠나요?
What... what is this?
뭐...이게 뭐야?
You're moving?
이사 중이신가요?
I'm moving into Ho-jin's house.
호진네 집으로 이사해요.
We discussed it in Canada.
우리는 캐나다에서 그것에 대해 논의했습니다.
I told him my housing contract fell through.
나는 그에게 말했다 내 주택 계약이 실패했습니다.
He agreed to let me stay at his place for a few months.
그 사람은 내가 자기 집에 머물도록 허락해줬어 몇 달 동안.
Why didn't you tell me about this?
왜 나에게 이것에 대해 말하지 않았습니까?
Because I figured you'd react just like this.
내가 알았으니까 당신은 이렇게 반응할 것이다.
You'd be pressing me for details on how he is and what he's doing.
넌 나한테 세부사항을 요구할 거야 그 사람이 어떤지, 무엇을 하는지에 대해요.
We'll be filming soon,
곧 촬영을 시작하겠습니다.
and, like it or not, you'll see each other.
그리고 좋든 싫든, 당신은 서로를 볼 수 있습니다.
How can you work together like this?
어떻게 이렇게 함께 일할 수 있나요?
I'm going to tonight's event alone.
오늘 밤 행사에는 나 혼자 갈 예정이야.
Don't follow me.
나를 따르지 마십시오.
Alone?
홀로?
But it's a concert sponsored by an advertiser.
근데 콘서트야 광고주의 후원을 받습니다.
I should be there to introduce you.
나는 당신을 소개하기 위해 거기에 있어야합니다.
You said you didn't want me pressing you for details.
당신은 나를 원하지 않는다고 말했어요 자세한 내용을 확인하려면 누르세요.
Leave before I bite your head off.
내가 네 머리를 물어뜯기 전에 떠나라.
Fine. I won't come.
괜찮은. 나는 오지 않을 것이다.
But text me once you get there.
하지만 도착하면 문자 주세요.
I'm laid out, all damp like wet laundry...
나는 누워있고, 젖은 빨래처럼 온통 축축해...
but he's nice and dry,
하지만 그 사람은 착하고 말랐어.
put back together neatly.
다시 깔끔하게 정리해보세요.
Are you sure Do Ra-mi was wrong and that you won?
정말 도라미가 틀렸나요? 그리고 당신이 이겼나요?
No.
아니요.
I lost.
나는졌다.
Run away!
도망쳐!
I shouldn't have listened to her...
나는 그녀의 말을 듣지 말았어야 했는데...
and run away.
그리고 도망가세요.
Hey, cut it out already. At this rate, I'll pop out.
야, 벌써 그만둬. 이대로라면 튀어나오겠습니다.
Why blame me when you're the one who ran away?
왜 나를 비난합니까? 네가 도망친 사람이 언제야?
Jin-suk, where are you? Are you running late?
진석아, 어디야? 늦게 가시나요?
Mr. Kim's here, and Mr. Oh from the publishing company.
김 선생님이 오셨어요. 그리고 출판사 오씨님.
I'm sorry. I can't go.
죄송합니다. 갈 수 없어요.
Come. Let's take a picture.
오세요. 사진을 찍자.
What?
무엇?
You called us here tonight.
당신이 오늘 밤 우리를 여기로 불렀습니다.
You begged, saying it'd lift your mood and that you had the invitations.
기분 좋아지겠다 애원했지 그리고 당신이 초대장을 받았다는 것입니다.
And you're the one who invited Mr. Kim and Mr. Oh as an apology.
그리고 초대한 사람은 바로 당신이에요 김씨와 오씨가 사과했다.
So why...
그럼 왜...
can't you come?
너는 올 수 없니?
I'm at the airport.
나는 공항에 있어요.
I'm headed to Santiago.
저는 산티아고로 향하고 있어요.
What?
무엇?
Ji-sun was right.
지선씨가 옳았습니다.
I did break up with her first.
나는 그녀와 먼저 헤어졌다.
JIN-SUK & JI-SUN
진석&지선
OUR STORY WILL BEGIN UNDER THE CLEAR SKIES OF JEJU
우리의 이야기가 시작됩니다 제주의 맑은 하늘 아래
AS WE SET OFF ON A NEW JOURNEY TOGETHER...
우리가 함께 새로운 여정을 시작하면서...
So the invitations are as you wanted.
그래서 초대장은 당신이 원하는대로입니다.
What else shall we do? Tell me all your wedding wishes.
또 무엇을 해야 할까요? 당신의 결혼 소원을 모두 말해 보세요.
This is all so sudden that I'm not sure we could make anything happen.
너무 갑작스러운 일이라 잘 모르겠어 우리는 무엇이든 일어날 수 있습니다.
Come on now.
지금 어서.
You insisted on getting married quickly.
빨리 결혼하자고 하셨어요.
Still, I'm not sure we should rush things like this.
그래도 잘 모르겠어 우리는 이렇게 서둘러야 해요.
Let's just get it over and done with.
그냥 끝내고 끝내자.
If we don't tie the knot right now, I don't think I'll ever want to.
지금 당장 매듭을 묶지 않으면 나는 결코 그러고 싶지 않을 것 같아요.
Why do you want to get married?
왜 결혼하고 싶나요?
Why?
왜?
You said you wanted to.
당신은 당신이 원한다고 말했다.
I was a coward,
나는 겁쟁이였다.
and I'm ashamed.
부끄럽습니다.
So I'm leaving
그래서 나는 떠난다
to do some self-reflection and penance.
자기 반성과 참회를 하려고 합니다.
Have a safe trip.
안전한 여행 되세요.
Don't cry in public, and don't get drunk and start yelling.
공공장소에서 울지 마세요. 술에 취해 소리 지르지 마세요.
Okay.
좋아요.
My dear younger brother Ho-jin.
사랑하는 동생 호진이.
You could do more of that yourself.
그 이상은 스스로 할 수 있습니다.
Do what?
무엇을 합니까?
The vinyl record. Why'd you stare at it with such a sad look in your eyes?
비닐 레코드입니다. 그걸 왜 쳐다봤지? 그렇게 슬픈 표정으로?
See you.
또 봐요.
I hope you have a rough time.
힘든 시간 보내시기 바랍니다.
- Good evening. - Hello.
- 좋은 저녁이에요. - 안녕하세요.
Goodness, how are you? It's been so long.
맙소사, 잘 지내세요? 너무 오랜만이에요.
How are you?
어떻게 지내세요?
Good, very good!
좋아, 아주 좋아!
How come your manager isn't with you?
왜 매니저가 당신과 함께 있지 않습니까?
- He had other business to attend to. - I see.
- 그 사람은 다른 일을 처리해야 했어요. - 알겠어요.
The Italian ambassador is here today. Would you like to say hello after?
오늘 이탈리아 대사가 왔습니다. 끝나고 인사드릴까요?
That'd be an honor.
영광이겠습니다.
Okay. I'll arrange a meeting.
좋아요. 제가 회의를 주선하겠습니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Ho-jin, we have a situation.
호진 씨, 사정이 생겼어요.
Could you please help us out?
우리를 좀 도와주실 수 있나요?
Sure. What is it?
확신하는. 그것은 무엇입니까?
Don't. I invited him here as a guest.
하지 않다. 나는 그를 손님으로 여기에 초대했습니다.
It'd be impolite to ask.
물어보는 건 무례한 일이겠죠.
We don't have an interpreter, so I'm unable to greet the theater staff.
저희는 통역사가 없습니다. 그래서 극장 관계자분들께 인사를 드리지 못했어요.
They'll arrive soon enough.
곧 도착할 거예요.
- They're at Chungmu-ro. - How far can it be?
- 충무로에 있어요. - 얼마나 멀리 갈 수 있나요?
Chungmu-ro is over an hour away!
충무로는 1시간여 거리!
You've been the ambassador for how long? Yet you still don't know Seoul geography?
대사로 활동한 지 얼마나 됐나요? 그런데 아직도 서울지리를 모르시나요?
Isn't there anyone from the embassy who can interpret for you?
대사관에는 아무도 없나요? 누가 당신을 위해 통역해줄 수 있나요?
I don't think they'll make it in time with the traffic and all.
내 생각엔 그 사람들이 제 시간에 도착하지 못할 것 같아 교통이니 뭐니.
Then would you like me to help?
그럼 제가 도와드릴까요?
That'd be lovely.
정말 좋을 것 같아요.
That would be fantastic.
정말 환상적일 겁니다.
- Thank you. - No problem.
- 감사합니다. - 괜찮아요.
I prepared some opening remarks for the concert.
개회사를 준비했어요 콘서트를 위해.
Could you just help with those?
그 일을 도와주실 수 있나요?
I'll just let the people I came with know, and then I'll get ready.
같이 온 사람들한테만 알려줄게. 그럼 난 준비할게.
Of course. Thanks a lot.
물론. 정말 감사합니다.
You're a lifesaver. Thank you.
당신은 생명의 은인입니다. 감사합니다.
- Do you come here often? - Me? No.
- 여기 자주 오시나요? - 나? 아니요.
- No? - What about you?
- 아니? - 당신은 어때요?
It's my first time.
처음이에요.
Unbelievable.
믿을 수 없는.
CAN THIS LOVE BE TRANSLATED?
이 사랑을 번역할 수 있나요?
The rascal's not coming.
그 악당은 안 와요.
Apparently, the ambassador and his wife are also fans of Do Ra-mi.
아무래도 대사가 그의 아내도 도라미의 팬이다.
- When I greet them... - Yes?
- 인사할 때.. - 응?
...an interpreter will be present, right?
...통역사가 참석할 예정이죠?
Yes, of course.
물론이죠.
There they are.
거기 있습니다.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
This is Ms. Cha Mu-hee.
차무희씨입니다.
Nice to meet you.
만나서 반가워요.
Thank you for coming.
와주셔서 감사합니다.
I'm a big fan of Do Ra-mi's.
저는 도라미 씨의 팬이에요.
Thank you for inviting me.
초대해주셔서 감사합니다.
Mu-hee, you must be exhausted.
무희, 피곤하시겠어요.
Oh dear.
이런.
You can skip the embassy bazaar that the ambassador's wife invited you to.
대사관 바자회는 건너뛸 수 있습니다. 대사 부인이 당신을 초대했다고요.
He was a different interpreter, right?
그 사람은 다른 통역사였죠?
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
Wasn't there a different interpreter at the start of the concert?
다른 통역사는 없었나? 콘서트 시작하자마자?
Well, I'm not sure.
글쎄요, 잘 모르겠습니다.
Was I seeing things again?
내가 또 뭔가를 본 걸까?
Hey, Joo Ho-jin!
안녕하세요, 주호진님!
Where might you be, Joo Ho-jin?
주호진 씨는 어디에 있나요?
Something came up, so I couldn't go to my seat.
뭔가 떠올랐는데, 그래서 나는 내 자리에 갈 수 없었다.
I'm in the parking lot. Could you ride with Mr. Oh to my place?
나는 주차장에 있습니다. 오 선생님과 함께 저희 집까지 차를 타고 가실 수 있나요?
No, Mr. Oh already left.
아니요, 오씨는 이미 떠났습니다.
Wait for me, Joo Ho-jin.
기다려주세요, 주호진님.
There it is.
거기 있습니다.
I'll be going, then.
그럼 난 갈게.
Wait, Mu-hee?
잠깐, 무희?
Going down.
내려갑니다.
Doors closing.
문이 닫힙니다.
Well, take care.
글쎄요, 조심하세요.
Which floor?
어느 층인가요?
I'm going to the same floor as you.
나도 너랑 같은 층에 갈 거야.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Don't mention it.
그것을 언급하지 마십시오.
Ms. Cha Mu-hee, right?
차무희 씨 맞죠?
- You know me? - Of course I do.
- 저를 아시나요? - 물론이죠.
Why, you're a famous actress.
왜요, 당신은 유명한 여배우이군요.
I was sitting next to you in the concert hall earlier.
나는 당신 옆에 앉아 있었다 아까 콘서트홀에서.
Next to that empty seat.
그 빈자리 옆.
I see.
알겠어요.
Yes.
예.
And I heard what you just said.
그리고 방금 당신이 말한 것을 들었습니다.
You were right.
맞아요.
It's not the same interpreter.
같은 통역사가 아닙니다.
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
I know the guy who was interpreting at the beginning.
나는 그 사람을 안다 처음에 통역을 하던 사람이요.
The empty seat between us
우리 사이의 빈자리
was actually his seat.
실제로 그의 자리였습니다.
And that guy is, well...
그리고 그 사람은 글쎄요...
Doors opening.
문이 열립니다.
It's that guy there.
거기 그 사람이에요.
Joo Ho-jin.
주호진.
What took you so long?
왜 그렇게 오래 걸렸나요?
We'd planned for a dinner of four here, but two people canceled.
우리는 여기서 4인 저녁 식사를 하기로 계획했는데, 그런데 두 사람이 취소했어요.
If someone as distinguished as you joins us, all the better.
당신처럼 뛰어난 사람이 있다면 우리와 함께하면 더욱 좋습니다.
Still, the owner of the house didn't invite me, so...
그래도 집주인은 나를 초대하지 않았으니...
Well, this house is practically mine.
글쎄, 이 집은 사실상 내 집이야.
It's only his on paper.
종이에 그의 것뿐입니다.
It's okay.
괜찮아요.
I must say, I am pretty hungry. I'll take the free meal, then.
나는 꽤 배가 고프다고 말해야 한다. 그럼 내가 공짜로 식사할게.
Marvelous.
기이.
Don't pay that guy any mind.
그 사람 신경 쓰지 마세요.
Just think of him as a manservant who works at this house.
그냥 하인으로 생각하세요 이 집에서 일하는 사람.
Please come in.
들어오세요.
This place will impress you. Just look at it.
이 곳은 당신에게 깊은 인상을 줄 것입니다. 그냥 보세요.
The person who built this house traveled all over the world
이 집을 지은 사람 전 세계를 여행했다
collecting old art, classical books, antiques,
오래된 미술품을 수집하고, 고전 서적, 골동품,
and even the vinyl records over there.
그리고 거기에 있는 비닐 레코드까지요.
This house is as good as a museum.
이 집은 박물관만큼 좋아요.
You mean Ho-jin's maternal grandfather, don't you?
당신 말은 호진이 외할아버지죠?
Yeah.
응.
Wait, you knew that?
잠깐, 그거 알고 있었어?
Have you been here before?
전에 여기에 와본 적이 있나요?
Once, just briefly.
한 번, 잠깐만요.
I see.
알겠어요.
Well then, you'll feel right at home.
그럼, 당신은 집에서 바로 느낄 것입니다.
Why are you standing around? Get on it and make us dinner.
왜 주위에 서 있습니까? 그걸 타고 저녁을 만들어 주세요.
Any preferences, Ms. Cha Mu-hee?
차무희 씨, 선호하는 것이 있나요?
I'm not too picky,
저는 별로 까다롭지 않은데,
but I do love spicy food.
하지만 나는 매운 음식을 좋아해요.
Spicy food?
매운 음식?
Did you get that? Anything spicy on the menu?
그거 알아냈어? 메뉴에 매운거 있나요?
Jin-suk chose tonight's menu, and it's Japanese.
진석은 오늘 저녁 메뉴를 골랐고, 그리고 일본어예요.
Japanese? Forget that.
일본어? 잊어버리세요.
Just do a spicy braised monkfish or stir-fried octopus.
그냥 매콤한 아귀찜을 해보세요 아니면 낙지볶음.
- How does that sound? - Sounds great.
- 어때요? - 좋은 것 같아요.
That works, right?
그거 효과가 있지, 그렇지?
No, I don't have monkfish or octopus.
아니요, 아귀나 문어는 없어요.
- Any blue crab? - None.
- 꽃게 있나요? - 없음.
- Cod? - Nope.
- 대구? - 아니요.
Squid, then?
그럼 오징어?
- I don't-- - You do!
- 난-- - 그렇군요!
- I don't.
- 나는 아니에요.
Then stir-fried squid it is. Make it spicy.
그 다음은 오징어볶음입니다. 매콤하게 만들어 보세요.
- How does that sound? - Sounds great.
- 어때요? - 좋은 것 같아요.
He's even a good cook, you know.
그 사람은 심지어 요리도 잘해요.
- I know. - My, my, you know everything!
- 알아요. - 어머, 어머, 당신은 다 아시잖아요!
You're a match made in... One moment.
당신은 일치합니다... 잠시만요.
Excuse me. I should get this.
실례합니다. 이걸 받아야 해요.
Yes, Mr. Oh?
네, 오 선생님?
Mr. Oh, don't come here. Go back.
아 씨, 여기 오지 마세요. 돌아가세요.
I'm almost there. I even brought Jeong, like you asked.
거의 다 왔어요. 요청하신 대로 정씨도 데려왔습니다.
Just turn around! Don't come here.
그냥 돌아서세요! 여기 오지 마세요.
Mr. Joo, can I help with anything?
주 선생님, 제가 무엇이든 도와드릴까요?
Should I chop this up?
이걸 잘라야 하나?
Go sit down. You're Mr. Kim's guest.
가서 앉으세요. 당신은 김 선생님의 손님이십니다.
Why are you even here anyway?
그런데 왜 여기에 있는 걸까요?
Mr. Kim asked me to come,
김 선생님이 오라고 하셔서
so I'm here for dinner.
그래서 난 저녁 먹으러 여기 왔어.
I'm just so hungry.
너무 배가 고파요.
Is that right?
그렇죠?
Sure. Let's say you're really hungry.
확신하는. 당신이 정말 배가 고프다고 가정해 보겠습니다.
Though, by my logic, you'd have to be starving to be here.
그래도 내 논리로는 여기 있으려면 굶어야 해.
Oh my!
이런!
What's this?
이건 뭐죠?
It looks delicious.
맛있어 보이네요.
It's just kelp broth. I haven't even started cooking.
바로 다시마육수입니다. 아직 요리도 시작하지 않았어요.
So it is.
그렇습니다.
Just like us.
우리처럼.
We're like broth with nothing but kelp. Not even started yet.
우리는 다시마만 넣은 국물과 같습니다. 아직 시작도 안 했어요.
Stop hovering here and go sit down. I'll feed you.
여기서 더 이상 머뭇거리지 말고 자리에 앉으세요. 내가 먹여줄게.
You turned it off?
당신이 그것을 껐나요?
Because I need to let it cool.
왜냐면 식혀야 하거든요.
It's for seasoning.
양념용이에요.
Mr. Joo Ho-jin?
주호진씨요?
I get that
나는 그것을 이해한다
I kept sneaking little sips of kelp broth
나는 계속해서 다시마 국물을 조금씩 마시고 있었다
and turned off the heat prematurely.
그리고 불을 일찍 꺼버렸어요.
But can't we let it boil a little longer instead of letting it cool?
하지만 좀 더 끓이면 안 될까요? 식히는 대신?
It'd be a waste to stop after just a taste.
멈추면 아깝지 맛만 본 후.
It would be a shame, wouldn't it?
부끄러운 일이겠죠, 그렇죠?
I think I turned it off and left it to cool at the perfect time.
내가 껐던 것 같아 그리고 딱 맞는 시간에 식혀 두었어요.
It's not a waste nor a shame.
그것은 낭비도 부끄러움도 아니다.
I mean, it's just water with kelp. There's nothing to it, really.
내 말은, 다시마가 들어간 물일 뿐이라는 거죠. 정말 아무것도 없습니다.
That's not true.
그것은 사실이 아닙니다.
I did
내가 그랬어
kiss you once!
키스 한번 해봐!
I was going to fry this.
이거 튀기기로 했는데
The concert must be over by now.
콘서트는 지금쯤 끝났을 거에요.
Should I try contacting Ms. Cha Mu-hee?
차무희씨한테 연락해볼까?
No. There's no need.
아뇨. 그럴 필요 없어요.
Once she finds out I'm in Seoul, she'll get in touch.
내가 서울에 있다는 걸 그 사람이 알게 되면, 그 사람이 연락할 거야.
Why not just reach out to her first? You did come all this way to see her.
그녀에게 먼저 연락하면 어떨까요? 당신은 그녀를 보기 위해 여기까지 왔어요.
Nanami, I didn't come here to meet that zombie.
나나미, 나 여기 안 왔어 그 좀비를 만나러.
I came to take photographs.
사진을 찍으러 왔습니다.
Look. Aren't the fall night lights beautiful?
바라보다. 가을 밤의 불빛이 아름답지 않나요?
You can take pictures of fall scenery anywhere in Japan.
가을 풍경을 사진에 담을 수 있어요 일본 어디든.
It's different.
그것은 다릅니다.
The cityscape is completely different.
도시 풍경은 완전히 다릅니다.
- You can see it through the camera. - Sure.
- 카메라를 통해 보실 수 있습니다. - 확신하는.
So you won't meet Ms. Cha Mu-hee before you leave?
그러니까 차무희 씨를 만나지 마세요. 떠나기 전에?
If she contacts me,
그 사람이 나한테 연락하면
I guess I could see her while I'm here.
내가 여기 있는 동안 그녀를 볼 수 있을 것 같아요.
It's spicy and delicious. Man, you're good.
매콤하고 맛있어요. 이봐, 당신은 괜찮아요.
You should've gone on Culinary Class Wars.
요리 계급 전쟁에 참여했어야 했어요.
I went on that family trip to Canada, too, back when he was young.
저도 캐나다로 가족여행을 갔었는데, 그가 어렸을 때.
So I guess you really are like family.
그래서 정말 가족 같은 사이인 것 같아요.
There's no doubt about it.
그것에 대해서는 의심의 여지가 없습니다.
Did you visit that park we went to back then?
그 공원에 가봤니? 우리 그때 갔었어?
- That's where they were filming. - Is that so?
- 그곳이 촬영 중이던 곳이에요. - 그렇습니까?
Then did you visit where we saw the double rainbow?
그럼 방문하셨나요? 우리가 쌍무지개를 어디서 봤지?
That waterfall.
그 폭포.
I wanted to, but I couldn't find it.
싶었지만 찾을 수 없었습니다.
That's too bad. It was such a splendid waterfall.
안됐네요. 정말 멋진 폭포였습니다.
A waterfall only you and I know about.
당신과 나만 아는 폭포
The waterfall is nice and cool.
폭포는 멋지고 시원합니다.
The waterfall we saw together
우리가 함께 본 폭포
was pretty too.
너무 예뻤어요.
It wasn't a waterfall.
폭포가 아니었습니다.
But we agreed to call it one.
그러나 우리는 그것을 하나로 부르기로 동의했습니다.
I'm done humoring your claim that all falling water is a waterfall.
당신의 주장을 유머러스하게 표현하는 건 끝났어요 떨어지는 물은 모두 폭포라는 것.
Hey.
여기요.
About the concert.
콘서트에 대해서.
Did you come to interpret because you knew I was coming?
통역하러 오셨나요? 내가 올 걸 알았기 때문에?
What are you thinking?
당신은 무엇을 생각하고 있습니까?
Why would I go there to interpret, knowing you'd be there?
내가 왜 거기 가서 통역을 하겠는가? 네가 거기 있을 줄 알았어?
You did that once before to meet me.
당신은 나를 만나기 전에 한 번 그랬습니다.
The answer is no.
대답은 '아니요'입니다.
Then why didn't you come sit?
그럼 왜 안 오셨어요?
I thought it'd be awkward.
어색할 거라 생각했어요.
Then why did you agree to let Yong-u move in?
그럼 왜 동의했나요? 용우를 들여보내려고?
If he's here, I'll come by often.
그 사람이 여기 있다면 자주 들를 것 같아요.
According to Yong-u, you've never been to his place,
용우에 따르면, 당신은 그 사람 집에 가본 적도 없고
so you'd never show up here.
그러니 당신은 여기에 절대 나타나지 않을 것입니다.
That's true.
그것은 사실이다.
Fine.
괜찮은.
So you came here with those mistaken assumptions?
그래서 여기 왔구나 그 잘못된 가정으로?
With such confidence?
그런 자신감으로?
I need that confidence to be able to sway you again.
그런 자신감이 필요해 당신을 다시 흔들 수 있도록.
You see,
알다시피,
rather than walk away with dignity,
당당하게 떠나는 것보다
I've decided to be the crazy bitch who sways you.
난 미친년이 되기로 결심했어 당신을 흔드는 사람.
Because...
왜냐면...
I'm placing my hope in the last thing you said to me that day.
난 마지막에 희망을 걸고 있어 그날 당신이 나에게 말했어요.
You said you were going to cross.
건너간다고 하더군요.
So...
그래서...
we did see a waterfall together!
우리는 함께 폭포를 봤어요!
I ought to visit a place like that at least once before I die.
그런 곳을 한번 가봐야겠어요 죽기 전에 적어도 한 번은.
You have though.
하지만 당신은 그랬습니다.
One of our drones fell into a ravine, and you and I fished it out. Remember?
우리 드론 중 하나가 계곡에 빠졌어요. 그리고 당신과 나는 그것을 알아냈습니다. 기억하다?
Oh yeah, we did.
아, 그래, 그랬지.
That was so rough. I said I'd never go back.
너무 거칠었어요. 나는 결코 돌아 가지 않을 것이라고 말했다.
But it looks great like this.
하지만 이렇게 보면 정말 멋져 보입니다.
That's why they say it's a comedy from afar
그래서 그들은 이렇게 말합니다. 멀리서 보면 코미디야
but a tragedy from up close.
그러나 가까이서 보면 비극이다.
The real tragedy is all the footage we haven't even started reviewing yet.
진짜 비극은 모두 영상이다 아직 검토도 시작하지 않았습니다.
My eyes are watering like they're about to pop out.
눈이 촉촉해 금방이라도 튀어나올 것 같은.
Don't cry.
울지 마세요.
Yong-u, thanks for always bringing the snacks.
용우님, 고마워요 항상 간식을 가져오니까.
Mu-hee looks great, so don't you worry.
무희는 정말 멋져보이니 걱정하지 마세요.
Thank you. And hang in there!
감사합니다. 그리고 거기에 버텨라!
- I'll clean up before I leave. - You don't need to.
- 떠나기 전에 청소할게요. - 그럴 필요는 없어요.
We should save some macarons for Producer Shin.
마카롱 좀 아껴둬야겠어 신 프로듀서에게.
Looks like another all-nighter for her.
그녀에게는 또 다른 밤새도록 하는 것 같습니다.
Starting tomorrow, she should be free during the day.
내일부터, 그녀는 낮에는 자유로울 것입니다.
Her fiancé went to Spain.
그녀의 약혼자는 스페인으로 갔다.
Spain? The writer Na Jin-suk?
스페인? 작가 나진석?
Yeah, he posted on Instagram that he's going to Spain. Santiago.
응, 그 사람 인스타그램에 올렸지 그 사람이 스페인에 간다고 하더군요. 산티아고.
I'm so freaking jealous.
정말 질투가 나네요.
Well, we're going to Italy.
음, 우리는 이탈리아로 갈 거예요.
We're going for work. Not to have fun.
우리는 일하러 갈 거예요. 재미를 위해서가 아닙니다.
NA JIN-SUK #SPAIN #SANTIAGO #CAMINO
나진석 #스페인 #산티아고 #카미노
Wow.
와우.
So she really is going around trying to cheat.
그래서 그 사람 진짜 돌아다닌다고 속이려고 합니다.
Hello, sir.
안녕하세요, 선생님.
- To Yeonnam-dong, please. - Sure.
- 연남동으로 부탁해요. - 확신하는.
Yes, Mr. Ahn.
네, 안 선생님.
I swung by the cutting room.
나는 편집실을 지나갔다.
Of course!
물론!
- They say the Canada footage looks great. - Yong-u.
- 캐나다 영상이 너무 좋다고 하더라고요. - 용우.
- They were singing her praises. - My bag, Yong-u!
- 그들은 그녀를 칭찬하고 있었어요. - 내 가방, 용우!
Italy has a totally different vibe from Canada,
이탈리아는 분위기가 완전 달라요 캐나다 출신,
so it should feel fresh.
그래서 신선하게 느껴져야 해요.
Sorry. I was on the phone with my boss, so I couldn't answer your call.
죄송합니다. 사장님이랑 통화중이었는데 그래서 나는 당신의 전화를 받을 수 없었습니다.
It's fine.
괜찮습니다.
Is that for working late?
늦게까지 일해서 그런 걸까요?
Those clothes.
그 옷.
I meant, are those clothes for you to wear while editing?
내 말은, 그 옷이요? 편집할 때 입을 수 있나요?
Not "work late" as in cheating.
부정행위처럼 "늦게까지 일"하지 마세요.
Sure.
확신하는.
Both outfits are for working late.
두 복장 모두 야근을 위한 것입니다.
Right.
오른쪽.
Editing and cheating.
편집 및 부정 행위.
You must be busy keeping up with both.
둘 다 따라가느라 바쁠 것 같아요.
Did you hurt yourself?
너 자신을 다치게 했니?
ATFL tears can be quite serious.
ATFL 눈물은 매우 심각할 수 있습니다.
An "ATFL tear"?
"ATFL 눈물"?
I told you I was an athlete.
나는 운동선수였다고 말했다.
It'll feel a bit better if you tape it. Shall I do it for you?
테이프로 붙이면 좀 나아질 것 같아요. 내가 당신을 위해 그것을 해줄까요?
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
What?
무엇?
Right.
오른쪽.
I couldn't tell earlier,
미리 말은 못했는데,
but it's starting to hurt.
하지만 아프기 시작했어.
Let me see.
어디 보자.
- Does that hurt? - Yeah.
- 그거 아프니? - 응.
Is an ATFL tear something I should be worried about?
ATFL 찢어짐인가 내가 걱정해야 할 게 뭔가?
It's just a fancy term for a sprained ankle.
그냥 멋진 용어야 발목 염좌의 경우.
Otherwise, you would've limped off.
그렇지 않으면 절뚝거리고 있었을 겁니다.
You said you were an athlete, didn't you? Which sport?
운동선수라고 했지, 그렇지? 어떤 스포츠?
- Shooting. - Did you do it for long?
- 촬영. - 오래 하셨나요?
I did it until I was conscripted. An injury ended my career.
징집될 때까지 그랬어요. 부상으로 내 경력이 끝났습니다.
After the army, my mom got me a job at her brother's firm.
군대 다녀온 뒤, 우리 엄마는 나에게 자기 남동생 회사에 일자리를 구해 주셨어.
Your mom's brother's company?
엄마 동생 회사야?
Then the CEO of your company is...
그렇다면 당신 회사의 CEO는...
Yes. CEO Ahn is my uncle.
그렇습니다. 안 대표는 나의 삼촌이다.
So you were family.
그래서 당신은 가족이었습니다.
That explains it.
그것은 그것을 설명합니다.
I wondered why a fresh-faced rookie was working with Ms. Cha Mu-hee.
왜 풋풋한 신인가 싶었어요 차무희씨와 함께 일했어요.
I might've gotten the job through nepotism,
내가 일자리를 얻었을지도 몰라 친족주의를 통해
but I've been with Mu-hee since she was a nobody.
하지만 난 무희랑 같이 있었어 그녀는 아무 것도 아니었기 때문에.
I cried with her, clutching her script after every failed audition.
나는 그녀의 대본을 붙잡고 그녀와 함께 울었다 오디션에 실패할 때마다.
Sorry. I take back calling you a fresh-faced rookie.
죄송합니다. 나는 당신에게 전화를 걸지 않습니다 갓 얼굴을 한 신인.
In that case, take back what you said about planning to cheat too.
그렇다면 당신이 한 말을 취소하세요. 속임수를 쓸 계획에 대해서도.
Now that I know what I know, it really bothers me whenever I see you.
이제 내가 아는 것을 알았으니, 당신을 볼 때마다 정말 괴로워요.
Were you keeping me occupied to stop me from cheating?
나를 계속 바쁘게 하고 있었나요? 내가 바람피우는 것을 막기 위해?
While going on about ATFL or whatever?
ATFL이나 뭐 그런 일을 진행하는 동안?
That
그
was because I knew you were hurt today.
오늘 네가 상처받은 걸 알았기 때문이야.
I wish I didn't know, but I do.
몰랐으면 좋겠지만 알고 있어요.
I heard he flew out today.
그 사람 오늘 비행기 나왔다고 들었어.
You said you'd cheat so you couldn't go back to him, didn't you?
넌 속일 거라고 말했지 그래서는 안 됐어 그 사람한테 다시 돌아가, 그렇지?
If you're struggling to move on, why not just take him back?
앞으로 나아가기 힘들다면, 그냥 그를 다시 데려가는 게 어때?
You're so out of it that you lost your bag and sprained your ankle.
넌 너무 정신이 없어서 가방을 잃어버렸어 그리고 발목을 삐었어요.
You didn't even get to cheat, and tonight, you'll be in the cutting room all night.
넌 바람피울 틈도 없었고, 오늘 밤에는 당신은 밤새도록 편집실에 있을 거예요.
Honestly, it's quite sad.
솔직히 좀 아쉽습니다.
Are you that worried about me?
너 내가 그렇게 걱정하는 거야?
Then will you help me?
그러면 당신이 나를 도와줄까요?
You're clearly interested in me.
당신은 분명히 나에게 관심이 있는 것 같습니다.
After I said I'd cheat,
내가 속이겠다고 말한 후,
haven't you been hanging around, hoping for a shot?
계속 놀고 있지는 않았어? 한 번 쏴볼까?
Okay, then. What if I agree to help? What will you do about it?
알았어, 그럼. 도움을 주기로 동의하면 어떻게 되나요? 그것에 대해 어떻게 하시겠습니까?
I'm a joke to you, aren't I?
나는 당신에게 농담입니다, 그렇죠?
It's not that you're a joke. I'm saying you can't do this.
당신이 농담하는 것이 아닙니다. 나는 당신이 이것을 할 수 없다고 말하고 있습니다.
Why not?
왜 안 돼?
When a shooting athlete aims at a target, it needs to be done with sincerity.
사격선수가 표적을 조준할 때, 성실하게 이루어져야 합니다.
"I'll hit the target no matter what. If I miss, I'll be the one who gets shot."
"나는 무슨 일이 있어도 목표를 달성할 것이다. 내가 놓치면 총에 맞는 사람은 내가 될 것이다."
But
하지만
you don't have that sincerity.
너에겐 그런 진심이 없어.
That's why when it's time to fire, you hesitate and can't pull the trigger.
그렇기 때문에 발사할 때가 되면 당신은 주저하고 방아쇠를 당길 수 없습니다.
Thanks for your help.
도움을 주셔서 감사합니다.
You pulled the trigger.
당신은 방아쇠를 당겼습니다.
Should I just contact Ms. Cha?
그냥 차씨에게 연락하면 될까요?
Don't!
하지 않다!
No matter what, don't contact her first!
무슨 일이 있어도 먼저 연락하지 마세요!
I'm not meeting that zombie until she asks to see me.
난 그 좀비를 만나지 않을 거야 그녀가 나를 만나자고 할 때까지.
Sure.
확신하는.
Cha Mu-hee.
차무희.
Why isn't she calling me?
왜 그녀는 나에게 전화하지 않나요?
After what she did to me on the plane that day...
그녀가 나에게 한 일 이후 그날 비행기에서...
You seem okay.
당신은 괜찮은 것 같습니다.
Hiro, it's too cold out.
히로, 밖이 너무 추워요.
Shall we eat too?
우리도 먹을까?
It'd warm us up.
그것은 우리를 따뜻하게 해줄 것입니다.
No, thanks.
아니요, 고마워요.
Ms. Cha Mu-hee
차무희씨
has not reached out.
도달하지 않았습니다.
Let's go back to the hotel.
호텔로 돌아갑시다.
TO CEO OH SEONG-CHEOL
오성철 대표님께
TO CHA MU-HEE, THE MOST BEAUTIFUL WOMAN IN THE UNIVERSE
차무희에게, 우주에서 가장 아름다운 여성
Here.
여기.
Next time, I'll give you Do Ra-mi merch with proper autographs.
다음엔 도라미 굿즈 드릴게요 제대로 된 사인과 함께.
Oh, that would be great.
아, 그러면 좋겠군요.
Here. This is my book.
여기. 이것은 내 책이다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
This is my first time meeting a novelist.
소설가를 만나는 것은 이번이 처음이다.
No, it isn't.
아니요, 그렇지 않습니다.
You've met him.
당신은 그를 만났어요.
You mean Mr. Joo Ho-jin?
주호진씨 말씀이신가요?
Mr. Joo Ho-jin, you wrote a book?
주호진씨, 책을 쓰셨나요?
Just once, in college.
딱 한 번, 대학에서.
But it won a prize and even became a bestseller.
그런데 상을 받았어요. 베스트셀러가 되기도 했습니다.
What's the title? I'd like to buy a copy.
제목이 무엇인가요? 사본을 사고 싶습니다.
You can't get it. It's out of print.
당신은 그것을 얻을 수 없습니다. 절판되었습니다.
I have a few copies.
나는 몇 장의 사본을 가지고 있습니다.
Come by my studio sometime.
가끔 내 스튜디오에 놀러오세요.
- I'll give you one. - Thank you.
- 내가 하나 줄게. - 감사합니다.
Can I post a photo on Instagram of this book you signed?
인스타그램에 사진을 올려도 될까요? 이 책에 당신이 서명했어요?
I'd be so grateful if you did.
그렇게 해주시면 정말 감사하겠습니다.
I follow you on Instagram. Should we follow each other?
나는 Instagram에서 당신을 팔로우합니다. 서로 따라가야 할까요?
I would really love to,
정말 그러고 싶습니다.
but if we do, your account could get a lot of heat.
하지만 그렇게 한다면, 귀하의 계정에 많은 열이 발생할 수 있습니다.
Is that so?
그렇습니까?
So you and Ho-jin don't follow each other?
그럼 호진이는 서로 팔로우 안 하는 건가요?
Mr. Joo Ho-jin doesn't follow me.
주호진씨는 저를 따라오지 않습니다.
Sure, he does.
물론이죠.
Right?
오른쪽?
Ho-jin, you follow her, don't you?
호진아, 따라오지?
I saw it on your account.
네 계정에서 봤어.
Mr. Joo Ho-jin, you're following me?
주호진 씨, 따라오시나요?
We made that bet
우리는 내기를 했어요
back in Japan.
다시 일본으로.
I followed you, as promised.
나는 약속대로 당신을 따랐습니다.
See?
보다?
I see.
알겠어요.
I had no idea.
나는 전혀 몰랐다.
Wait, you didn't know that?
잠깐만요, 그걸 몰랐나요?
I have quite a few followers, so...
팔로워가 꽤 많아서...
Oh boy, Joo Ho-jin!
아, 주호진!
You were just one of many!
당신은 단지 많은 사람 중 하나였을 뿐이에요!
Look. I'm sorry.
바라보다. 죄송합니다.
As we promised that day, I should follow you back,
그날 우리 약속대로 난 당신을 따라가야 해요,
but it'd be a little--
하지만 그건 좀--
You don't have to. Please don't.
그럴 필요는 없습니다. 그러지 마세요.
You should've accepted when she first offered.
당신은 받아들였어야 했어요 그녀가 처음 제안했을 때.
If the two of you are done with your tea, you should go.
둘이서 차 한잔 마시고 나면 너는 가야 해.
No, I haven't finished my tea yet.
아니요, 아직 차를 다 마시지 않았습니다.
Mu-hee, take your time with that.
무희, 천천히 하세요.
Mr. Kim, the time is...
김 선생님, 시간이...
The time?
시간?
This is the time? It's almost time for my show to air.
지금이 시간인가? 내 쇼가 방송될 시간이 거의 다 됐어요.
- Divorce Your Husband. - You watch that too, Mr. Kim?
- 남편과 이혼하세요. - 당신도 봤어요, 김 선생님?
Goodness, of course! It's excellent. I always bawl my eyes out.
물론이죠! 훌륭해요. 나는 항상 눈을 떴다.
- Exactly. - Why don't we watch some TV together?
- 정확히. - 우리 함께 TV를 보는 게 어때요?
- Shall we? - Let's.
- 갈까? - 하자.
Wait. Where did I put my glasses?
기다리다. 내가 안경을 어디에 두었나요?
I think I left them in your car earlier.
제가 아까 당신 차에 그것들을 두고 온 것 같아요.
You seem to be enjoying yourself, but you should call it a day and go home.
즐기고 계시는 것 같은데, 하지만 하루만 투자하고 집에 가야 합니다.
Yeah?
응?
Then, since I'm out here anyway, I'll get going.
그럼 어차피 난 여기 있으니까 나는 갈 것이다.
Head on in. Don't leave her all alone.
안으로 들어가세요. 그녀를 혼자 두지 마세요.
Mr. Kim.
김 씨.
You left your seat empty earlier to avoid her, didn't you?
아까 자리를 비워 두셨네요 그 사람을 피하려고 그랬지?
Do you find that young lady hard to read?
그 젊은 아가씨를 읽기가 어렵다고 생각하시나요?
You once told me that every person speaks their own language.
당신은 한때 나에게 모든 사람이 자신의 언어를 사용합니다.
I did.
그랬어요.
I don't think I understand her language very well.
내 생각엔 아닌 것 같아 나는 그녀의 언어를 아주 잘 이해합니다.
I approached thinking she was interested, but she turned me down.
그 사람이 관심이 있는 줄 알고 접근했는데, 하지만 그녀는 나를 거절했어요.
I avoided her, taking that as rejection,
나는 그것을 거절로 여기고 그녀를 피했다.
but now she's here, acting like that.
그런데 지금 그녀는 여기 와서 그런 식으로 행동하고 있어요.
Is she interested in me again, or does she feel bad for turning me down?
그 사람이 또 나한테 관심이 있는 걸까, 아니면 그 사람이 나를 거절해서 기분이 안 좋은 걸까?
I can't really tell.
나는 정말로 말할 수 없다.
I have no idea what to say to her once I'm inside.
나는 그녀에게 무슨 말을 해야할지 모르겠어요 일단 내가 안에 들어가면.
It must be frustrating not being able to understand her.
답답할 텐데 그녀를 이해할 수 없다는 것.
But
하지만
are you fine with not understanding her? Aren't you an interpreter?
그 사람을 이해하지 못해도 괜찮나요? 당신은 통역사가 아니신가요?
If it's a language you don't know, you should study it.
모르는 언어라면 당신은 그것을 공부해야합니다.
The vocabulary, syntax,
어휘, 구문,
and punctuation will all differ from those of the language you speak.
구두점은 모두 다릅니다 당신이 말하는 언어에서.
Look closely and try your best to understand.
자세히 봐 그리고 최선을 다해 이해하려고 노력하세요.
The weather is lovely.
날씨가 정말 좋아요.
Isn't the song lovely too?
노래도 너무 멋지지 않나요?
Mr. Joo Ho-jin.
주호진 씨.
I'm going to head off now.
이제 출발하겠습니다.
Where's Mr. Kim?
김 선생님은 어디 계시나요?
He left.
그는 떠났다.
I didn't even get to say goodbye.
저는 작별 인사도 하지 못했습니다.
Thanks so much for dinner. It was delicious.
저녁 식사 정말 감사합니다. 맛있었습니다.
I'll be going.
나는 갈 것이다.
One second.
1초.
We need to talk.
우리는 이야기를 해야 합니다.
Why are you so jittery?
왜 그렇게 불안해?
What is that?
저게 뭐에요?
That.
저것.
What? It's the book Mr. Kim gave me earlier. Why?
무엇? 그 책이에요 아까 김 선생님이 주셨어요. 왜?
Something's up. Let me see.
문제가 발생했습니다. 어디 보자.
What? This is mine.
무엇? 이건 내꺼야
- You're clearly hiding something. - What?
- 뭔가 숨기고 있는 게 분명해요. - 무엇?
- Let's see.
- 어디 보자.
What's that over there?
저기 저거 뭐야?
Wow.
우와.
Okay, I stole it. How'd you even see that, Eagle Eyes?
알았어, 내가 훔쳤어. 그걸 어떻게 보셨나요, Eagle Eyes?
I looked closely with the intention of studying
자세히 보니 공부하겠다는 마음으로
and caught a thief.
그리고 도둑을 잡았습니다.
You really have a knack...
너 정말 재주가 있구나...
for driving me insane.
나를 미치게 만들어서.
If you're not going to turn me in, can I have my book back?
나를 제출하지 않을 거라면, 내 책을 돌려받을 수 있나요?
I'm embarrassed and just want to go.
부끄러워서 그냥 가고 싶어요.
You're giving me this?
나한테 이걸 주는 거야?
It was always yours.
그것은 항상 당신의 것이었습니다.
I bought it as a gift for you.
당신을 위한 선물로 샀어요.
I didn't think I'd get to give it to you, but here you are, stealing it yourself.
내가 너한테 그걸 줄 수 있을 거라고는 생각도 못했는데, 그런데 여기 당신이 직접 훔치고 있습니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
For dinner and the gift.
저녁식사나 선물로.
I should repay you for what you've given me.
갚아야지 당신이 나에게 준 것에 대해.
I'll treat you to a delicious meal and give you a gift next time.
맛있는 식사를 대접하겠습니다 그리고 다음에는 선물을 주세요.
Next time?
다음번?
Yong-u!
용우!
You said Yong-u's moving in here.
용우 씨가 여기로 이사 온다고 하셨어요.
At the housewarming,
집들이때,
I'll bring some good food and a gift.
맛있는 음식과 선물을 가져오겠습니다.
Then see you next time.
그럼 다음에 또 만나요.
Next time?
다음번?
She left this behind.
그녀는 이것을 남겨두고 왔습니다.
Oh no. I only brought the sleeve.
안 돼. 소매만 가져왔습니다.
Am I an idiot?
나는 바보입니까?
PAPAGO♥
파파고♥
You took the sleeve and left the record behind.
소매를 가져가셨어요 기록을 남겼습니다.
Will you steal this next time?
다음번엔 이걸 훔칠 건가요?
I forgot because I was in a rush to leave.
급하게 떠나느라 잊어버렸어요.
It may be hard to believe,
믿기 어려울 수도 있지만,
but I didn't leave it behind on purpose this time.
하지만 난 그걸 남겨두지 않았어 이번에는 일부러.
How far did you get?
얼마나 멀리까지 오셨나요?
I'm almost home.
집에 거의 다 왔어요.
Then wait in front of your place. I'll bring it to you.
그럼 집 앞에서 기다리세요. 제가 가져다 드리겠습니다.
Sorry? What?
죄송해요? 무엇?
Now?
지금?
Yes.
예.
Send me your address.
주소를 보내주세요.
I'll head over there now.
나는 지금 거기로 갈 것이다.
You don't have to go out of your way to come here.
굳이 애쓰지 않아도 돼 여기로 오려고.
I'm already in my car. Should I get out?
나는 이미 차 안에 있어요. 나가야 하나?
No. If you're in your car anyway, you might as well come.
아니요. 어쨌든 차 안에 있다면 당신이 올 수도 있습니다.
I'm coming. Wait for me.
나는 간다. 기다려주세요.
Mu-hee?
무희?
Your uncle is here.
당신의 삼촌이 여기 있습니다.
PAPAGO♥
파파고♥
Your call cannot be completed.
통화를 완료할 수 없습니다.
You will be forwarded to voicemail and charged after the beep.
음성메일로 전달됩니다. 신호음이 울린 후 충전됩니다.
Your call cannot be completed.
통화를 완료할 수 없습니다.
You will be forwarded to voicemail and charged after the beep.
음성메일로 전달됩니다. 신호음이 울린 후 충전됩니다.
JOO HO-JIN
주호진
Hey, Mr. Joo.
안녕하세요, 주 씨.
Why is it so hard to reach you?
당신에게 연락하는 것이 왜 그렇게 어려운가요?
Oh, things were so hectic that I didn't notice my phone was dead.
아 일이 너무 바빴어요 내 휴대폰이 죽은 걸 몰랐다는 거죠.
Have you been calling? I'm sorry.
전화는 해보셨나요? 죄송합니다.
I think something's up with Ms. Cha. I can't reach her.
차씨에게 무슨 일이 있는 것 같아요. 나는 그녀에게 연락할 수 없습니다.
Mu-hee?
무희?
She's at a photo shoot right now.
그녀는 지금 사진 촬영 중입니다.
- What? - She's getting her hair and makeup done.
- 무엇? - 그녀는 머리와 화장을 하고 있습니다.
Wanna talk to her?
그녀와 이야기하고 싶나요?
No. As long as she's okay, it's fine.
아뇨. 그녀가 괜찮다면 괜찮습니다.
Actually, an article was published today.
사실 오늘 기사가 나왔어요.
It covers a touchy subject for her, so I guess she didn't answer.
그녀에게는 민감한 주제를 다루고 있습니다. 그래서 그녀는 대답하지 않은 것 같아요.
But don't worry.
하지만 걱정하지 마세요.
She's still her cheerful self.
그녀는 여전히 쾌활한 모습이다.
She is?
그녀는?
PAPAGO♥
파파고♥
I knew things were tense with your family, but that article was a surprise.
나는 당신의 가족이 긴장된 상황이라는 것을 알았습니다. 그런데 그 기사가 충격적이었어요.
Reporters showed up at my uncle's house.
기자들이 삼촌 집에 나타났습니다.
I'm under his family register. I guess they thought they were my parents.
나는 그의 호적에 속해 있습니다. 아마 그 사람들은 내 부모님인 줄 알았던 것 같아요.
THE GLAMOROUS FAMILY HISTORY OF AN ACTRESS BORN INTO WEALTH
화려한 가족 역사 부유하게 태어난 여배우
But the article is in your favor. Claims you were born into wealth.
하지만 기사는 당신에게 유리합니다. 당신이 부유한 집안에서 태어났다고 주장합니다.
These days, being bold and fabulous works. Everyone loves you even more.
요즘은 대담하고 멋진 작품들이 나오고 있습니다. 모두가 당신을 더욱 사랑합니다.
Cha Mu-hee is loved.
차무희는 사랑받고 있다.
Is that right?
그렇죠?
That's good.
좋아요.
By the way, Ho-jin called.
그런데 호진이가 전화를 했어요.
He was worried that he couldn't reach you.
그는 당신에게 연락할 수 없을까 걱정했습니다.
Did the two of you plan to meet up?
두 사람이 만날 계획이 있었나요?
I wanted to...
싶었는데...
but I won't be seeing him.
하지만 난 그 사람을 만나지 않을 거예요.
I stood him up.
나는 그를 일으켰다.
Do you really
정말로요?
not remember what happened to your mom and dad?
무슨 일이 일어났는지 기억나지 않는다 엄마 아빠한테?
No smiling!
웃지 마세요!
You disgust me.
당신은 나를 역겨워합니다.
That's me.
저예요.
That picture was taken on my birthday.
그 사진은 내 생일에 찍은 사진이에요.
That's my house.
거긴 내 집이야.
The flowers I grew
내가 키운 꽃
and my chicks.
그리고 내 여자들
Dad came home for the first time in a while
아빠가 집에 오셨어요 오랜만에
with a birthday present for me.
나를 위한 생일 선물
Mu-hee!
무희!
- Happy birthday to you - Daddy!
- 생일 축하합니다 - 아빠!
- A teddy bear? I love it!
- 테디베어요? 나는 그것을 좋아한다!
- Happy birthday! - It's so cute.
- 생일 축하해요! - 너무 귀여워요.
You're the best, Dad!
당신은 최고예요, 아빠!
Eat up.
먹어라.
You're so cute.
당신은 너무 귀여워요.
Mom?
엄마?
Serves you right, you liar.
제대로 봉사하는구나, 거짓말쟁이야.
You sneaky devil.
이 교활한 악마야.
You lied, pretending you didn't remember a thing,
당신은 거짓말을 했어요 아무것도 기억하지 못하는 척,
and now you're scared you'll get caught.
그리고 이제 당신은 잡힐까봐 두렵습니다.
You felt uneasy, didn't you?
당신은 불안감을 느꼈죠, 그렇죠?
When people started loving the likes of you.
사람들이 사랑을 시작했을 때 당신이 좋아하는 것.
You don't believe it, do you?
당신은 그것을 믿지 않습니까?
That they'll keep loving you.
그들이 당신을 계속 사랑할 것이라는 것.
I only emerged because you're so pathetic.
당신이 너무 한심해서 내가 등장한 것뿐입니다.
Leave it all to me. After all, everyone loves Do Ra-mi.
나에게 모두 맡겨주세요. 결국 모두가 도라미를 좋아하는 거죠.
Ms. Cha Mu-hee, shall we begin?
차무희씨, 시작해볼까요?
Sure.
확신하는.
She still hasn't reached out. What should I do?
그녀는 아직 연락하지 않았습니다. 어떻게 해야 하나요?
Just call her.
그냥 전화하세요.
And set up a meeting.
그리고 회의를 준비하세요.
I debated leaving, but I'm just too curious.
헤어질까 고민하다가 하지만 너무 궁금해요.
Let's do this!
해보자!
I'm curious too.
나도 궁금하다.
About what?
무엇에 대해서?
What happened between you and Ms. Cha Mu-hee on the plane?
당신 사이에 무슨 일이 있었나요? 그리고 차무희 씨는 비행기에 계셨나요?
I choose you.
나는 당신을 선택합니다.
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
I'm watching the Do Ra-mi movie to get some footage of Mu-hee.
도라미 영화를 보고 있어요 무희의 영상을 찍으러.
But this... I'm watching it again, and it's still terrifying.
그런데 이거... 또 보고 있는데, 그리고 그것은 여전히 ​​끔찍합니다.
Of course it is. She's a zombie. A killer zombie.
물론 그렇습니다. 그녀는 좀비입니다. 킬러 좀비.
Yeah, she kills way too many people.
그래, 그녀는 너무 많은 사람을 죽였어.
But Do Ra-mi herself only kills one person.
그런데 도라미 본인은 딱 한 사람만 죽인다.
The man she loved.
그녀가 사랑했던 남자.
Mr. Kim?
김 선생님?
Mr. Kim, is that you?
김 선생님, 혹시 당신인가요?
Ma'am?
부인?
Today's not the day you usually come
오늘은 평소에 네가 오는 날이 아니야
to clean.
청소하다.
Ms. Cha Mu-hee?
차무희씨?
What are you doing here?
여기서 뭐하는거야?
If I tell you to wait,
기다리라고 하면,
wait in the spot I told you to wait until I show up.
내가 기다리라고 한 그 자리에서 기다려 내가 나타날 때까지.
I don't know what vibe you're going for today,
모르겠어요 오늘은 어떤 분위기로 갈까?
but I won't be humoring you anymore.
하지만 더 이상 당신을 유머러스하게 하지 않을 거예요.
Please leave.
떠나주세요.
Vibe? I like that kind of thing.
바이브? 나는 그런 것을 좋아한다.
Yesterday's vibe was "beggar thief." What do I seem like today?
어제 분위기는 '거지도둑'이었어요. 오늘 나는 어떤 모습인가?
Have a guess.
추측해 보세요.
Are you unwell?
몸이 안 좋으세요?
See? You're so kind.
보다? 당신은 정말 친절해요.
I wasn't being kind.
나는 친절하지 않았습니다.
No, you're kind. That's why she's pining for you.
아니, 당신은 친절해요. 그래서 그녀는 당신을 갈망하고 있습니다.
"I felt like I might die if someone was kind to me."
"죽을 것 같았어. 누군가 나에게 친절했다면."
"It felt like kindness might kill me."
"친절이 나를 죽일 수도 있을 것 같았어요."
Not me though.
하지만 나는 아닙니다.
I...
나는...
simply kill.
그냥 죽여.
And who exactly
그리고 정확히 누가
are you?
당신은?
Today's vibe...
오늘의 분위기...
is Do Ra-mi.
도라미입니다.
CAN THIS LOVE BE TRANSLATED?
이 사랑을 번역할 수 있나요?
Subtitle translation by: Jimin Choi
자막 번역: 최지민